[
    {
        "question": "What is the area of Madagascar, in square angstroms?",
        "answer": "32",
        "unit": "square angstroms"
    },
    {
        "question": "How tall, in feet, is the 22nd tallest building in the world?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "feet"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is 7<sup>43</sup>?",
        "answer": "36",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the mass of Mars in iPhone 5s?",
        "answer": "25",
        "unit": "kg"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many Apps have been downloaded from Apple's iTunes Store?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many different sets of 5 can you pick from a group of 50?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "sets"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 2004, how many people worldwide died in motor vehicle accidents?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "people"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many seconds has it been since Thomas Jefferson was born?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "seconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many stories tall is the tallest human ever to live?",
        "answer": "0",
        "unit": "stories"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many atoms are in your body?",
        "answer": "28",
        "unit": "atoms"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many chicken wing segments were consumed during the 2013 Super Bowl?",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "segments"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many bytes of digital information does humanity produce each day?",
        "answer": "18",
        "unit": "bytes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the estimated size, in bytes, of the library of Congress in 1949?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "bytes"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you were to count from one to a quintillion, and took a second to visualize each number (audibly counting would take a lot longer), how long would it take, in years?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "years"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many kegs (as in beer) could you fill with the amount of liquid the average person drinks in a year?",
        "answer": "1",
        "unit": "kegs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hurricane Sandy was devastating and expensive. If you had a pile of pennies equal in value to Sandy's cost, what would be its weight in troy ounces?",
        "answer": "12",
        "unit": "troy ounces"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the population of the world's 70th most populous nation?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "million"
    },
    {
        "question": "United Airlines is the largest airline in the world. How many planes comprise their fleet?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "planes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the average February high temperature in Washington DC, in °D?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": "°F"
    },
    {
        "question": "The My Lai Massacre occurred on this date in 1968. According to the US army, how many people were killed?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many automobiles had General Motors produced as of this date in 1968?",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": "automobiles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What fraction of earth's water supply is contained within living beings (all forms of life)?",
        "answer": "-4",
        "unit": "fraction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Archimedes famously placed an upper bound on the number of grains of sand needed to fill the entire universe: One vigintillion. How many grains of sand did he suggest?",
        "answer": "63",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many different types of proteins are in the human body?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many different amino acids are?",
        "answer": "1",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many hairs are on the average human head?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "hairs"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many ml of saliva does a human produce in a lifetime? ",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "ml"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many red blood cells are in one human body?",
        "answer": "13",
        "unit": "trillion"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many toothpicks can be made from a cord of wood?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many seconds does it take a dog to locate the direction of a sound?",
        "answer": "-3",
        "unit": "seconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many taste buds are on a human tongue?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": "taste buds"
    },
    {
        "question": "The diameter of a DNA molecule in inches.",
        "answer": "-4",
        "unit": "inches"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many base pairs are in one nucleus of one cell?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "base pairs"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many diapers are thrown out in the U.S. each year?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "billion"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many years is the ½ life of Carbon-14?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": "years"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many years does it take for Styrofoam to biodegrade?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": "years"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the amount of energy used in kWh for the average search query on Google?",
        "answer": "-4",
        "unit": "kWh"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many gallons of gasoline are burned each day?",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "gallons"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many active volcanoes are on the surface of the earth?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the age of the Earth in seconds?",
        "answer": "17",
        "unit": "seconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "The number of Earths that would fit inside of the sun?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "Earths"
    },
    {
        "question": "The approximate weight of a 150lb person if they were able to stand on the surface of the sun?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "lbs"
    },
    {
        "question": "The number of years ago that Pangaea existed as a supercontinent?",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": "million years"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed of the Earth in miles per hour that it travels through space?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "miles per hour"
    },
    {
        "question": "111,111,111<sup>2</sup>",
        "answer": "16",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many pounds of food are eaten by one human in one lifetime?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "pounds"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mass of the earth in tons?",
        "answer": "22",
        "unit": "tons"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many ways can you make change for a dollar?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many dimples are on a U.S. regulation golf ball?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times will you blink this year?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the speed of a sneeze in cm/s?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "cm/s"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many kilometers long is the Great Barrier Reef?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "kilometers"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many tons one cubic cm of a neutron star would be?",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": "tons"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed of light in m/s.",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": "m/s"
    },
    {
        "question": "Number of galaxies in the universe.",
        "answer": "11",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "Pounds of skin shed by a person in his or her lifetime.",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": "pounds"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many seconds would it take a heavy object to sink into the deepest part of the ocean?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "seconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "The number of neutrinos that are produced from the sun that pass through your body while you read this sentence.",
        "answer": "15",
        "unit": "neutrinos"
    },
    {
        "question": "Number of miles the universe expands in one hour.",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "The number of stars in our solar system.",
        "answer": "0",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "Average number of seconds a Koala spends sleeping each day",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "seconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "The number of atoms in one mole.",
        "answer": "24",
        "unit": "atoms"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many seconds will it take to fully and quickly write out the number of 1 google if you were not allowed to use scientific notation?",
        "answer": "1",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many feet above sea level is the highest point of Florida?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": "feet"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many square miles are the 48 contiguous U.S. states?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "square miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many people in the U.S. are unemployed?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "million"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the population density (people per square mile) in the country of Mali?",
        "answer": "1",
        "unit": "people per square mile"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many miles are between Stockholm and Paris?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many toothpicks are required to cover a baseball diamond if the tooth picks are lying flat and sideby-side?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum weight, in tons, of a Giant Sequoia tree?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "tons"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many 7-11 stores are there in Virginia?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "stores"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many babies are born each year in the world?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "million"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many stone blocks were used to build the pyramid at Giza?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "blocks"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many milk cows are in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "million"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many steps does the average American walk during their lifetime?",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": "million"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many dollar bills would need to be stacked to reach the moon?",
        "answer": "12",
        "unit": "bill"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many tennis balls does it take to cover the playing surface of a tennis court (including the doubles alley)?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum speed of the garden snail in mph?",
        "answer": "-2",
        "unit": "mph"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many metric tons of fish are caught in the country of Jordan each year?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "metric tons"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many decimeters deep is the Marianas Trench?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "decimeters"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many liters of water are there is an Olympic-sized swimming pool?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "liters"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many federal, state, and local governmental employees are there in the U.S.? ",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many popular votes separated Obama and McCain during the 2008 presidential election?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "million"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many car miles were avoided in 2010 by buses that took kids to school?",
        "answer": "11",
        "unit": "miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the volume of the average adult in dekaliters?",
        "answer": "1",
        "unit": "dekaliters"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the annual interest that is owed on the national debt each year were divided equally amongst all U.S. citizens, how much would each citizen owe?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": "dollars"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many troy ounces of gold were produced last year?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "troy ounces"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many earths are needed to have the equivalent weight of one Sun?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "earths"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many gas stations are there in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "stations"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many golf balls will fit in a 747?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many cups of coffee does Starbucks sell each year?",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "cups"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many watts of solar power are/were produced in the U.S. today at noon?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "watts"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many stars are in the Milky Way Galaxy?",
        "answer": "11",
        "unit": "billion"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many kilometers does light travel between two consecutive visits of Haley's comet?",
        "answer": "15",
        "unit": "kilometers"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many electrons flow through a 3 Amp wire each minute?",
        "answer": "21",
        "unit": "electrons"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many milligrams does the earth weigh?",
        "answer": "31",
        "unit": "milligrams"
    },
    {
        "question": "What percent of the world's water is in rivers?",
        "answer": "-4",
        "unit": "%"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many farms are there in Virginia?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many miles of railroad are operational in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many different species of spiders and scorpions are there in the world?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many cells die naturally (apoptosis) in your body during the time that it takes you to solve the\naverage Fermi problem?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many joules does the sun emit per second?",
        "answer": "26",
        "unit": "joules per second"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the frequency of an FM radio signal, in cycles per second?",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": "cycles per second"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the wavelength of an FM radio signal, in meters?",
        "answer": "0",
        "unit": "meters"
    },
    {
        "question": "Forrest Gump ran from the coast of Maine to Los Angeles. How many steps did he take?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many stacked 2 x 4 LEGO blocks would it take to reach the height of the Empire state Building?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "Now how many standard 2x4 LEGO blocks would I need  to make an actual-size replica of the Empire state Building?",
        "answer": "11",
        "unit": "LEGO blocks"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long, in hours, does it take for a beam of light to traverse the continental U.S.?",
        "answer": "-6",
        "unit": "hours"
    },
    {
        "question": "How old is the Earth, in seconds?",
        "answer": "17",
        "unit": "seconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many nanometers span the entire range of visible light?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": "nanometers"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many nanometers are in a megaparsec?",
        "answer": "31",
        "unit": "nanometers"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many milliliters of blood does the American Red Cross collect in the US in a given year?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "milliliters"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many atoms of lead would make a ton of lead?",
        "answer": "27",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many paperclips would I need to make a chain long enough to reach the moon from the Earth?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "paperclips"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many drops of water are in a full bathtub?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many bones are in the human body?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many miles of highway make up the US Interstate Highway system?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": "miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "Estimate the mass in grams of all the fans at a home Phillies game.",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "grams"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many days would it take you to count to a million?",
        "answer": "1",
        "unit": "days"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many electrons pass through a 100 watt light bulb in a minute? ",
        "answer": "22",
        "unit": ""
    },
    {
        "question": "How many dollars would a quadrillionaire have?",
        "answer": "15",
        "unit": "dollars"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is 7e<sup>7</sup>?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many leaves are on a mature, healthy oak tree?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "leaves"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the area (in cm<sup>2</sup>) of the leaves on a mature, healthy oak tree?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "cm^2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming each leaf gets full sunlight, how much energy (watts) does it get from the sun in one year? ",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": "watts"
    },
    {
        "question": "I bought a 2 terabyte hard drive. How many bytes of information can it hold?",
        "answer": "12",
        "unit": "bytes"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many light-years is the distance from the Earth to the Sun?",
        "answer": "-5",
        "unit": "light-years"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is [ln(2)]<sup>30</sup>?",
        "answer": "-5",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "Two people stand on opposite sides of the Earth. What is the gravitational force between them?",
        "answer": "-21",
        "unit": "N"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many cases of food-borne botulism occur in the United States annually?",
        "answer": "1",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lethal dose of botulism toxin, in grams, for a 150 pound human?",
        "answer": "-7",
        "unit": "grams"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Census of Marine Life, with a membership of about 1000 scientists in 70 countries, what is the estimated number of life forms in the world's oceans?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many different species of fish did the Census of Marine Life discover in the past year?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many Christmas trees were produced in Ohio last year?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "trees"
    },
    {
        "question": "If one were to move closer and closer while observing isolated blood cells, at what distance, in meters, would they first come into clear view?",
        "answer": "-5",
        "unit": "meters"
    },
    {
        "question": "If one were to move closer and closer to a carbon atom, at what distance, in meters, would the nucleus appear?",
        "answer": "-12",
        "unit": "meters"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what distance from Earth's surface, in meters, can an astronaut observe the entire hemisphere directly beneath him/her?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "meters"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1983, more than 300 years after the first serious measurement attempt the Seventeenth General Congress on Weights and Measure defined the meter as as the distance light travels through a vacuum during a time interval of how many seconds?",
        "answer": "-9",
        "unit": "seconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much voltage can a large electric eel produce?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "volts"
    },
    {
        "question": "Up to how many MeV may the energy of gamma rays extend during the course of nuclear reactions initiated by low energy particles?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "MeV"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the distance, in meters, of a satellite in geosynchronous orbit about the Earth?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "meters"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the distance from the Sun to Pluto measured in meters?",
        "answer": "13",
        "unit": "meters"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the U.S. Bureau of the Census, what was the resident population of the United States on 1/1/2005?",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": "million"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the average diameter of a human hair in millimeters?",
        "answer": "-1",
        "unit": "millimeters"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many square kilometers of Lake Erie are solely under the jurisdiction of the USA?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": "square kilometers"
    },
    {
        "question": "A 15.0 cm long cylindrical glass tube, sealed at one end is filled with ethanol (d=.789g/ml). The mass of ethanol needed to fill the tube is found to be 9.64g. What is the inner diameter of the tube in centimeters?",
        "answer": "0",
        "unit": "cm"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the mass in grams of all the hydrogen atoms in 5.0 molecules of sucrose, C<sub>12</sub>H<sub>22</sub>O<sub>11</sub>?",
        "answer": "-22",
        "unit": "g"
    },
    {
        "question": "Municipal Solid Waste Generation has become a big problem. How many pounds of landfill waste would be generated by the population of Cuyahoga county in one year?",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "pounds"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the number of injuries in 2001 from skateboards in the U.S.? [Estimates calculated from a representative sample of hospitals with emergency treatment departments in the United States. Data are estimates of the number of emergency room treated cases nationwide associated with various products. Product involvement does not necessarily mean the product caused the accident.]",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "cases"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the annual consumption of ice cream, in pounds, for the State of Ohio?",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": "pounds"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the ratio of meters of the highest and lowest point in Colorado compared to the highest and lowest point in Minnesota?",
        "answer": "1",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the average rate of continental drift, in meters per day, along the Mid-Atlantic Ridge?",
        "answer": "-4",
        "unit": "meters per day"
    },
    {
        "question": "Determine the density of oxygen in the air of this room at 25°C and 760 torr in g/L.",
        "answer": "0",
        "unit": "g/L"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many total kg of carbon monoxide were produced in 2001 in the US as Air Pollutant Emissions?",
        "answer": "11",
        "unit": "kg"
    },
    {
        "question": "What fraction of a cubic meter is a milliliter?",
        "answer": "-6",
        "unit": "m^(-3)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the length, in meters, of the shortest form of an X-ray wavelength?",
        "answer": "-11",
        "unit": "m"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the range, in meters, between the longest and shortest wavelengths of visible light within the electromagnetic spectrum?",
        "answer": "-7",
        "unit": "meters"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many breaths does the average U.S. adult take in a lifetime?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "billion"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many seconds were cell phones used in 2003 by the U.S. population?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "seconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many organic and inorganic substances were registered with the Chemical Abstracts service as of Jan. 1, 2005?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the number of somatic cells in a 49 day old, normally developing fetus?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many genes are currently considered part of the human genome?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "The diameter of a chromium atom is about 2.4 Å (10 Å = 1nm). How many chromium atoms would have to be lined up to span 1.0 cm?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "angstrom"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many hydrogen atoms are present in 1 mg of aspartame (C14H18N2O5), the artificial sweetener?",
        "answer": "19",
        "unit": "atoms"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the mass, in grams, of all electrons within a single copper atom?",
        "answer": "-26",
        "unit": "grams"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many microseconds would it take to count to a trillion, if you count 100 numbers in 1 minute?",
        "answer": "18",
        "unit": "microseconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many gallons of milk is produced in the United States each year?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "gallons"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many hours of sleep does an average person get in a life time in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "lifetime hours"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world demand for oil in gallons each year?",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "gallons"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many millimeters are there in one (1) degree of latitude at 40 degrees North latitude?",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": "millimeters"
    },
    {
        "question": "125! = ",
        "answer": "209",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How much would $1,000 be worth if it was compounded annually at an interest of 8% for 50 years?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": "dollars"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many people in the U.S. have the five most common last names in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "million"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum depth in meters of the Gulf of Mexico?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "meters"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the national debt were represented with a stack of $1 bills, how far would the stack reach in miles?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "18.7 billion texts are sent each day around the world. How many of these texts are sent each day from the U.S.?",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "billion"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many milliliters per year of bottled water are purchased/drank per person in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "milliliters"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many golf balls can fit in a school bus?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "golf balls"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the total length of all hairs shed by a cat in a month in cm?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "cm"
    },
    {
        "question": "One suggestion for putting satellites into orbit cheaply without using rockets is to build a tower 300 km high containing an elevator. One would put the payload in the elevator, lift it to the top, and just step out into orbit. Ignoring other problems (such as structural strain on the tower), estimate the weight of such a tower if its base were the size of Washington DC and it were made of steel. (Steel is about 5 times as dense as water, which has a density of 1 gm/cm<sup>3</sup>.)",
        "answer": "15",
        "unit": "million metric tons"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the total number of millimeters that runners run who cross a finish line in a marathon?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "mm"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many revolutions does a car tire make in an hour traveling 100 kilometers per hour?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "revolutions per hour"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many platelets are in each liter of human blood?",
        "answer": "11",
        "unit": "per liter"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many red blood cells does the U.S. Congress have?",
        "answer": "16",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "2<sup>24</sup> / 3<sup>24</sup> =",
        "answer": "-4",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "8<sup>88</sup> =",
        "answer": "79",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many paper bags are made from 14 million trees?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "bags"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many lawyers are there in the United States?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "thousand"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much carbon dioxide in grams is emitted annually into the atmosphere by all U.S. power plants?",
        "answer": "15",
        "unit": "grams"
    },
    {
        "question": "Intel factories produce enough transistors per year for each man, woman, and child on earth to have 20 million. How many transistors are being produced per year?",
        "answer": "17",
        "unit": "million"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many milliliters of water are in the Great Lakes",
        "answer": "19",
        "unit": "milliliters"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the number of deer killed by hunters in North Carolina last season divided by the human population of North Carolina?",
        "answer": "-2",
        "unit": "deer/human"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are odds of having a deer-vehicle collision in North Carolina in the next 12 months?",
        "answer": "-3",
        "unit": "null"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many grams of feces is produced annually by hogs in North Carolina?",
        "answer": "13",
        "unit": "grams"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many texts are sent every hour of every day worldwide, not including app-to-app messaging?",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "hours"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many school buses to equal the weight of the sun ?",
        "answer": "26",
        "unit": "school buses"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the acceleration caused by Earth's gravity divided by free fall acceleration of the Sun?",
        "answer": "-2",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many red blood cells are needed to blanket the surface area of an M&M?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "cells"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many playing cards are needed toblanket the surface area of a doubles tennis court?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What is 137 to the power of 56?",
        "answer": "119",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many electrons are there in our Sun?",
        "answer": "57",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many electrons are there in our Sun?",
        "answer": "57",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many toothpicks could be made from a telephone pole?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "You're over the Mariana trench in a boat with a cannonball in your hand. You drop it overboard, how long does the cannonball take to reach the bottom in seconds?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "seconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many minutes will be spent texting (solely texting) in one year by high school students in the United States?",
        "answer": "11",
        "unit": "minutes"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many new passenger cars are sold each year in the USA",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "million"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many aluminum drink cans are used each year in the world?",
        "answer": "11",
        "unit": "billion"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mass of a typical aluminum can is about 0.018 kg. What is the total mass of aluminum in a year's consumption from these cans.",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "kg"
    },
    {
        "question": "Silas Marner saved his pennies until they covered the 48 contiguous states of the United States. How many pennies did he have?",
        "answer": "16",
        "unit": "pennies"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many new telephone numbers became available when the three-digit area code system was installed?",
        "answer": "12",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "During the time interval of a blink, how many km has light travelled in a vacuum?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "km"
    },
    {
        "question": "A typical family Bible consists of 1,000 pages with an average of 5,000 characters and spaces per page. If it takes 100 Fe atoms to define a character, how many Bibles can fit on the head of a pin?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": "Bibles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the volume of the Moon in cubic meters?",
        "answer": "19",
        "unit": "cubic meters"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many hours elapse from one full moon to the next?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "hours"
    },
    {
        "question": "How far, in km, does light travel during the time it takes between full moons?",
        "answer": "12",
        "unit": "km"
    },
    {
        "question": "Relative to the sun, what is the Earth's orbital velocity in miles per hour?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "miles per hour"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many kilometers would theEarth have travelled during the time it takes between full moons?",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": "kilometers"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under favorable conditions, the bacterium SO (short for Scientificus Olympiadum) will reproduce in 6 minutes. Assuming they don't die, how many SO bacteria can claim the same ancestor after 1 day?",
        "answer": "433",
        "unit": "bacteria"
    },
    {
        "question": "The SO bacterium is rod-like with dimensions of 4x104 cm, 104 cm, and 0.5x104 cm. What is the weight, in grams, of an SO bacterium?",
        "answer": "-12",
        "unit": "grams"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many SO bacteria would be able to be packed into a ping pong ball?",
        "answer": "13",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "The SO bacterium is special because it has a tiny brain which is about the same percentage of its total weight as an adult human's. Estimate the weight, in grams, of the brain of an SO bacterium",
        "answer": "-14",
        "unit": "grams"
    },
    {
        "question": "The SO bacteria need a living space of about 30x104 cm in all directions to thrive. How many of these thriving bacteria might be found in a gram of pond water?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "bacteria per gram of pond water"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the SO bacteria don't die, how many hours will it take for two to reproduce and make a volume equal to that of the earth?",
        "answer": "0",
        "unit": "hours"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times could a basketball player bounce a ball during her teenage years if she didn't stop to eat, sleep, etc.?",
        "answer": "8",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "If all the rain that falls during a typical summer rainstorm were gathered into a single drop, what would the drop’s radius be?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "mm"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a large ship (oil tanker / cargo ship / aircraft carrier / etc.) is placed into the ocean, how much does the global sea level rise?",
        "answer": "-10",
        "unit": "millimeters"
    },
    {
        "question": "Archimedes of Syracuse was a philosopher, inventor, and scientist who lived and died in Sicily more than 2,000 years ago. Assuming that the earth’s atmosphere has been thoroughly mixed since then, how many molecules from his final breath are in your lungs right now?",
        "answer": "1",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many airline passengers are in the air over the United States right now?",
        "answer": "6",
        "unit": "passengers"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the kinetic energy stored in continental drift?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the kinetic energy stored in all the wind in the Earth’s atmosphere? The specific gravity of air is 1/1000 th that of water. You should only consider the atmosphere’s motion relative to the surface of the Earth, and not the overall rotation of the planet.",
        "answer": "20",
        "unit": "Joules"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sunlight exerts a force of 1 micronewton per square meter. Ignoring friction, how long would it take a car powered by this force to go from 0 mph to 60 mph (or, equivalently, from 0 kph to 100 kph)?",
        "answer": "11",
        "unit": "seconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many babies are born in New Haven on an average day?",
        "answer": "1",
        "unit": "day"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many trees are there in Connecticut?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "Despite what you may have learned in chemistry class, any pair of atoms will stick to each other to form a diatomic molecule. Given this fact, how many species of diatomic molecules are there?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "You have a one-­‐liter bottle of water. What is the area you could cover with this water if it were spread to be one molecule thick?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "m²"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long a line can an average pencil make in kilometers?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": "kilometers"
    },
    {
        "question": "If all the soda that is drunk in the United States during a typical day were gathered into a single drop, what would the drop’s radius be in meters?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": "m"
    },
    {
        "question": "If all the soda that is drunk in the United States during a typical day were gathered into a single drop, what would the drop’s radius be in meters?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": "m"
    },
    {
        "question": "If electric energy costs $0.1 per kilowatt hour, and is delivered to your home at a voltage of 120 Volts, what is the cost of one electron? ",
        "answer": "-24",
        "unit": "cents per electron"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many piano tuners are there in Chicago?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What is pi to the power of 9?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many pounds of rice were consumed by people living in the U.S. last year?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "pounds"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many board game dice does it take to equal the mass of the average human?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": "board game dice"
    },
    {
        "question": "What number of tennis balls would you have to lay on the surface area of an Olympic-sized pool in order to fully cover it?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "tennis balls"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much trash (in pounds) does the average family produce in a year?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "pounds"
    },
    {
        "question": "What volume of air (in Liters) do you breathe in one day?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "Liters"
    },
    {
        "question": "If we could brew coffee in swimming pools, how many pools would we need to satisfy the need in the U.S. on a given day?",
        "answer": "2",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many pennies would it take to make a stack the height of the Empire State Building?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "pennies"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many centimeters are in 40,000 miles?",
        "answer": "10",
        "unit": "cm"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the probability that you will end up with the exact same card sequence as you started after shuffling it?",
        "answer": "-68",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "Calculate 10<sup>100</sup> - 10<sup>99</sup> - 10<sup>98</sup> - ... - 10<sup>1</sup>.",
        "answer": "100",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many bird species are there in North America?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "species"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many molecules of ATP are used in an average human in one day?",
        "answer": "26",
        "unit": "molecules"
    },
    {
        "question": "Compute 2<sup>2<sup>2<sup>2<sup>2</sup></sup></sup></sup>",
        "answer": "19728",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many fish are there, on average, per meter cubed of water in the Earth's ocean?",
        "answer": "-6",
        "unit": "fish/m^3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the worldwide coffee bean production in picograms?",
        "answer": "25",
        "unit": "picograms"
    },
    {
        "question": "Norway is the 118th most populous country in the world. What is the population of Norway?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "million"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is 75<sup>56</sup>?",
        "answer": "105",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many different ways are there to arrange 8 objects in a circle?",
        "answer": "4",
        "unit": "arrangements"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times more massive is the Sun than the Moon?",
        "answer": "7",
        "unit": "times"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many carbon atoms would it take in order to create a single-file line of atoms around the Earth?",
        "answer": "17",
        "unit": "atoms"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the force required to break a covalent bond, in Newtons?",
        "answer": "-9",
        "unit": "Newtons"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much mass, in kg, is the Sun losing every second?",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "kg/s"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many grams of cheese does Wisconsin produce every day?",
        "answer": "9",
        "unit": "grams"
    },
    {
        "question": "As of 2017, how many minutes of movie has Steven Spielberg directed?",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": "minutes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assume that in a game of Rock-Paper-Scissors, the hands played by both participants are chosen completely randomly with an equal chance of choosing Rock, Paper, or Scissors. If the two choose the same hand, they do another round. What is the probability the two play the same hand exactly 72 times before finally declaring a winner?",
        "answer": "-35",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "Surface area of an iPhone in hectares",
        "answer": "-6",
        "unit": "null"
    },
    {
        "question": "26<sup>9</sup>",
        "answer": "13",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "Mass of a mole(unit) of moles(animal) in ounces",
        "answer": "24",
        "unit": "ounces"
    },
    {
        "question": "How mnay credit cards would fit in the stratosphere",
        "answer": "25",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "A sample of pure iridium weighs as much as a bread loaf. How many atom of iridium are in this sample?",
        "answer": "24",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "Electron diameter in light years",
        "answer": "-32",
        "unit": "null"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many individual fries does McDonald's sell yearly",
        "answer": "12",
        "unit": "billion"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many exa-newtons of force does the Earth’s gravitational field apply on a single grain of rice located on the surface of the Moon?",
        "answer": "-25",
        "unit": "exa-newtons"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times does the string “cell” appear in Campbell’s Biology, 9th edition? (Note: any word that contains “cell”, such as “intracellular” or “cellulose”, would count)",
        "answer": "3",
        "unit": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How many standard AAA batteries would it take to equal the total installed wind energy capacity of the world?",
        "answer": "5",
        "unit": "batteries"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many cells are in the typical human body?",
        "answer": "13",
        "unit": "trillion"
    },
    {
        "question": "If every person who ever lived crowded together in one spot, how much area would be covered, in terms of the area of Rhode Island?",
        "answer": "1",
        "unit": "the area of Rhode Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many pennies would it take to create a walkable bridge from Boston, MA to Portugal, assuming that pennies sink (and that you therefore must stack pennies from the bottom of the ocean floor)",
        "answer": "16",
        "unit": "pennies"
    }
]